Rhon Vincent Y. Ramos

Alexandria, VA
(571)-2439236
rhonvyramos@gmail.com
github.com/rhonvyramos
www.linkedin.com/in/rhon-vincent-ramos
https://resume-portfolio-rhon-ramos-1d7a22731ce3.herokuapp.com/

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with a long, educational background in programming. Completed a six month Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp at George Washington University and Bachelor's degree holder in Information Science with a 3.5 GPA. Experienced with iOS mobile development, with emphasis on user accessibility. Effective at working with groups of any size, including solo, in Agile methodologies. Extremely punctual in scheduling and ensures all tasks would be done within the allotted time frame. Possessed strong leadership, management, commitment, and teamwork qualities honed by years of experience working as a Martial arts Instructor.

Technical Skills

Object Oriented Programming, Data Analysis, HTML, CSS, React.js, Node.js, Handlebars, Inquirer, Java, JavaScript, Express, JSON, jQuery, ApolloServer, GraphQL, MySQL, NoSQL, IndexedDB, MongoDB, Sequelize, REST, Swift, SwiftUI, Xcode, GitHub, GitBash, Visual Studio Code, Postman, JUNIT, TDD Unit Testing, Waterfall, Agile, TDD, and SCRUM methodologies

Relevant Work experience
Enhance-IT Atlanta, GA
iOS Developer
(Feb 2002 – Mar 2023)

- Applied Apple's Swift development language to code native apps for iOS platform.
- Brainstormed new application concepts based on available development assets and historical successes.
- Worked with teams of various sizes utilizing Agile methodology.
- Applied Unit Tests onto existing and newer software components.
- Researched and selected APIs for integration into development projects.
- Developed in-house projects involving REST APIs and Database Management.
- Studied and implemented further improvements to User Accessibility, including. text-to-speech and screen readability.

Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp George Washington University (EdX) Full-Stack Web Developer (May 2023 – Oct 2023)

Projects

Event Scheduler "uFree"

github.com/hafsah1976/uFree

Link: ufree-f24a66c626ea.herokuapp.com

- A robust event scheduler with a focus on matching participant time availability.
 Responsible for much of the frontend visuals and client-to-server functionalities.
 Assisted in laying the foundations for maintenance on client-side logic.
- React, GraphQL, ApolloServer, MongoDB

Character Creator

github.com/Z-Alfadl/Character-Creator

Link: character-creatornator-b75c37ca8524.herokuapp.com

- A fun character creator where users can create and share characters for literature, tabletop roleplaying games, and other recreational activities.
- Focused on writing and maintaining the middleware responsible for the applications requests and retrieval from a MySQL-ran database.
- Express, MySQL, Sequelize
- News Article Search Engine

News Article Search Engine

github.com/rhonvyramos/libel_news_reports Link: rhonvyramos.github.io/libel_news_reports

- A simple news article search engine that uses publicly available news article APIs.
 Emphasizes user agency in writing their own notes about an article that would be saved on the browser itself.
- Implemented Inquirer and HTML forms as part of the search engine function for this application. Utilizing Inquirer, JavaScript, REST API, LocalStorage

Education

Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp George Washington University (EdX) (May 2023 – Oct 2023)

Bachelor's degree in Information Science Graduate University of Maryland, College Park (Sep 2019 – Jun 2021)

Associate degree in computer science Montgomery College, Germantown (Sep 2017 – Jun 2019)